Raoul family papers, 1865-1985
Emory University
- Letters and personal papers, 1865-1982, Series 1; Boxes 1-35, OP 1-2
  - Sarah Lois Wadley papers, 1874-1920, Subseries 1.3; Personal name.; Boxes 5-10
    - 1892, August-December (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 1893, January-April (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 1893, May-September (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1893, October-December (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 1894, January-April (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 1894, May-August (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 1894, September-December (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1895, January-March (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 1895, April-August (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 1895, September-December (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 1896, January-May (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - 1896, July-September (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 1896, October-December (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 1897, January-June (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 1897, July-September (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - 1897, October-December (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - 1898, January-April (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - 1898, September-December (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - 1899, January-July (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - 1899, August-December (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - 1900, January-July (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - 1900, August-December (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - 1901, January-June (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - 1901, July-December (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - 1902, January-April (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1902, May-August (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1902, September-December (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1903, January-June (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1903, July-December (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1904, January-June (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 1904, July-December (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1905, January-June (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 1905, July-December (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 1906, January-May (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - 1906, July-December (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - 1907, January-April (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1907, June-September (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1908, February-May (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1908, June-October (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1909-1911 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1913, January-June (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1913, July-November (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1914, January-May (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - 1914, June-December (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - 1915, January-May (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 1915, June-December (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - 1917, January-April (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1917, May-November (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 1918, January-June (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1918, July-December (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1919, January-June (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1919, July-December (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 1920, January-June (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 1920, July-November (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Undated letters to Mary Wadley Raoul (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
    - Undated letters to Raoul family members (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Letters from various persons, 1867, 1884-1920 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Other papers
    - Diary extracts, 1859-1862 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Mary Raoul Millis papers, 1879-1934, Subseries 1.4; Personal name.; Boxes 11-17
    Mary Raoul Millis, the oldest Raoul daughter, was born January 22, 1870, in Livingston Parish, Louisiana. She first attended day schools in Savannah and later spent two years at boarding school in Chestnut Hill, Pennsylvania. Her 1889 debut in New York was followed by a year in Europe (1890-1891). In 1893, she married John Millis, an officer with the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. She spent the next twenty years in the various locations where he husband was stationed by the army. Mary left John Millis and moved to Atlanta in 1914, where she remained until her death in 1962. In 1909, under the influence of her brother William Greene Raoul, Jr., Mary joined the Socialist Party. She continued her association with the Party in Georgia, serving as state secretary from 1915 to 1919, presidential elector in the general election of 1928, state representative for the campaign committee of 1932, and educational director of the Atlanta local in 1933. In 1933, she also chaired the Angelo Herndon Freedom Committee. Mary was the mother of three children, Ralph Millis (1894-1938), historian Walter Millis (b. 1899), and Janet Millis (b. 1903).
    Papers of Mary Raoul Millis include letters to her mother and other family members, letters from her husband John Millis), and letters from friends and relatives. Also included are papers relating to her involvement with the American Civil Liberties Union and the Socialist Party in the early 1930's. Correspondence relating to her last illness (1957-1958) is located in Subseries 1.12, papers of Eleonore Raoul, and copies of her family memoir and unfinished autobiography can be found in Series 4.
    Mary Raoul Millis' letters, written primarily to her mother, cover the fifty years from 1879 to 1929. The majority fall between 1886 and 1912, the period of her adolescence and her nearly twenty years as an army wife. The early letters discuss studies, beaux, social events, family activities and travels to New Orleans (1886, 1893), Mexico (1887, 1892), and Europe (1890-1891).
    The letters following Mary's marriage to John Millis in 1893 give many details about life at the various posts where he was assigned - New Orleans (1893-1894), Washington, D.C. (1894-1898), Willets Point, New York (1898-1900), Seattle (1900-1905), Manila (1905-1907), and Cleveland (1908-1912). The Seattle letters are particularly descriptive of life and society in this city at the turn of the century. Lengthy journal letters (1905) document the Millis family's voyage to the Philippines, stops in Japan and China, and their early experiences in Manila. Other letters from this period concern army life on the Islands and the return voyage to the United States via Hong Kong (1907). The Cleveland letters (1908-1912) concern Mary's interest in Socialism and Christian Science and reflect her increasing unhappiness in marriage which led to a separation in 1912.
    John Millis' letters to Mary, written during the period of their courtship and early marriage (1893-1900), concern his work supervising levee and channel construction on the Mississippi and Red Rivers (1893-1894), activities with the Light House Board in Washington, D.C. (1894-1898), and frequent inspection tours. Other letters to Mary from friends, Wadley relatives, and her mother-in-law, Jane Millis, concern social events, Mary's marriage, and Raoul and Millis genealogy (1896-1897). Additional genealogical data on the Millis family is located among the miscellaneous material in this box, as are Mary's early writings.
    The American Civil Liberties Union correspondence is primarily between Mary Raoul Millis and ACLU director Roger Baldwin (1931-1933). Topics include the formation of a civil liberties committee in Atlanta, chain gang abuses, the Scottsboro trial, a raid on the International Labor Defense's Atlanta offices, blacks and the local Atlanta police situation, and Mary's refusal to serve as state chairman of the ACLU in Georgia because of the race issue (1933). Correspondence relating to the Socialist Party in Georgia is mainly between Mary Raoul Millis and Clarence Senior, executive secretary of the party. Most of the letters concern plans, activities, the election of 1932 and Norman Thomas's candidacy, and the status of the Party in Georgia, Alabama, and the South in general. Many of Mary's letters discuss the problems of organizing blacks into the Party in Georgia, a step which she opposed. Miscellaneous materials relating to the Socialist Party include lists, bylaws, campaign literature and election ballots.
    - Letters to Mary Wadley Raoul
    - 1879-1885 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 1886, March-June (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 1886, September-October (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - 1886, November-December (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - 1887, January-February (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - 1887, March-April (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - 1887, October-December (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - 1888-1889 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - 1890-1891 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - 1892 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - 1893 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - 1894, January-March (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - 1894, April-July (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - 1894, October-December (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - 1895, January-March (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 1895, April-July (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 1895, August-December (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 1896, January-June (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 1896, August-December (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 1897, January-June (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 1897, July-September (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 1897, October-December (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - 1898, January-May (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 1898, June-September (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - 1898, October-December (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 1899, January-June (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - 1899, July-December (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - 1900 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - 1901, January-February (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1901, March-May (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1901, June-August (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1901, September-December (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 1902, January-April (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - 1902, May-September (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 1902, October-December (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 1903, April-August (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - 1903, September-December (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - 1904, January-April (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - 1904, May-July (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - 1904, August-December (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - 1905, January-May (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - 1905, June-September (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - 1905, October-December (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - 1906, January-May (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1906, June-August (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1906, September-December (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1907, January-March (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1907, May-November (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 1908, March-July (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 1908, August-December (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 1909, January-May (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 1909, June-December (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - 1910, January-May (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - 1910, June-December (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - 1911, January -June (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - 1911, July-October (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - 1912 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - 1922-1925 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - 1926-1929 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Undated (Pre-1894; New Orleans; Washington, D.C.; Willets Point, N.Y.; Seattle) (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Undated (Manila; Japan) (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Undated (Cleveland) (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Letters from John Millis, 1893-1894
    - 1893, March-June (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1893, July-August (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1893, September (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1893, October (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1893, November (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - 1894, July (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - 1894, August (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - 1894, September (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - 1894, October-December (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - 1895, January-June (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 1895, July (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 1895, August-October (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 1896, January-June (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 1896, July (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 1896, August (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - 1897 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - 1898, February (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - 1898, March (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 1898, August-November (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - 1899-1900 and undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Letters from various persons
    - 1885-1888 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1889 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1890-1891 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1892 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1893 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1894-1895 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - 1896-1897 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - 1898 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - 1899 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - 1900-1901 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - 1902 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - 1903-1904 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - 1905-1907 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Undated (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
    - American Civil Liberties Union - Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Socialist Party - Correspondence, 1920, 1928-1932, July (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Socialist Party - Correspondence, 1932, August-September (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Socialist Party - Correspondence, 1932, October-1934 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Socialist Party - Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous (general) (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - William Greene Raoul, Jr. papers, 1880-1949, Subseries 1.5; Personal name.; Boxes 18-19
    William Raoul, Jr. was born in Macon, Georgia, on April 30, 1872. He received his education at various Savannah and New York schools and the Lawrenceville School in New Jersey, from which he was expelled in 1889. After working for a year in the New York architectural firm of Bradford Gilbert, he rejoined the family in Atlanta in 1893. In the mid-1890's, William endeavored unsuccessfully to establish a career in the developing Southern textile industry. He worked in cotton mills in Atlanta, Lindale, Roswell, and West Point, Georgia, and spent a brief apprenticeship at mills in Lawrence and Lowell, Massachusetts. His next business venture was with the Southern Saw Works in East Point, Georgia, from 1899 to 1901. William was secretary-treasurer of the firm and also mayor of East Point during this period. After 1902, he was associated with the South Atlantic Car and Manufacturing Company in Waycross, Georgia. While in Waycross, he became interested in Socialism and devoted the next several years to Socialist activities, editing a Socialist newspaper in Birmingham in 1910 and organizing for the Socialist Party of Montana in 1911. Subsequent ventures included homesteading, shipping and investing in the New York stock market, where he made and lost a sizeable fortune between 1924 and 1930. He made his home in various places after 1911 settling finally near Atlantic Highlands in New Jersey. William was married first to Ruth Cunningham from 1901 until her death in 1905. His second marriage in 1915 to his first cousin, Winifred Wadley, ended in divorce on March 12, 1917. On March 16, 1917, he married Margaret Lente of New York. William had one child, a son John Cummingham (b. 1901), who lived only a few hours.
    Spanning the years 1880 to 1949, papers of William Greene Raoul, Jr. include letters to his mother and other members of the family as well as miscellaneous materials. Several folders of letters from his wife Ruth Cunningham Raoul to her mother-in-law are also located in the subseries.
    William Raoul's early letters were written from the Lawrenceville School in New Jersey (1888), from New York City (1892-1893), from the Chicago World's Fair (1893), and from the family's new home in Atlanta (1893-1894). Letters from Lowell, Massachusetts recount his experiences in the "card" and "picker" rooms and his attempts to supervise the mill hands (1895). Subsequent letters concern his work with the Southern Saw Works in East Point, Georgia (1899-1901), and the Irwin County Cotton Mills and the South Atlantic Car and Manufacturing Company in Waycross, Georgia (1902-1906). These latter letters discuss his financial and marital difficulties as well.
    William Raoul's letters for 1910 and 1911 relate almost entirely to his newly-embraced Socialism. Letters from Birmingham where he edited a Socialist newspaper, The People's Voice, discuss his activities and friends, his philosophical ideas, and his upbringing (1910). Letters written from Kansas, Colorado, Wyoming, Washington, and Montana discuss the status of Socialism in the West and his activities as an organizer for the Socialist Party of Montana (1911). There are only scattered letters after 1911.
    Miscellaneous materials include handbills for William's appearances in Montana and a typescript sketch, "Uncle Loring: Georgia Scene of the 1880's." Ruth Cunningham Raoul's letters to her mother-in-law (1902-1904) written from Asheville and various Georgia towns, primarily concern her health problems and miscarriage.
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - Letters of William Greene Raoul, Jr.
    - 1880-1891 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 1892, March-October (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 1892, November-December (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - 1893, January-April (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - 1893, May-August (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - 1894-1895 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - 1896, 1898-1899 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - 1900, January-March (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - 1900, June-September (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - 1901-1902 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - 1903-1904 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - 1905-1909 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1910, January-April (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 1910, May-September (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - 1911 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 1913-1949 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Letters of Ruth Cunningham Raoul
    - 1902-1903 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - 1904, January-June (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - 1904, July-October (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Gaston C. Raoul papers, 1882-1959, Subseries 1.6; Personal name.; Boxes 20-22
    Gaston C. Raoul was born March 1, 1874 at Great Hill Place in Bolingbroke, Georgia. He attended schools in Savannah, the Lawrenceville School in New Jersey, and the Georgia Institute of Technology. Between 1890 and 1903, Gaston held a variety of positions with railroads in Kentucky, Mexico, Georgia, Alabama, and New York. After a brief stint with the ship brokerage firm of J. F. Minis and Company in Savannah, he settled permanently in Chattanooga in 1905. There he headed a refrigerator and furniture manufacturing concern, known variously as the Keyser Manufacturing Company, the Odorless Refrigerator Company, the Tennessee Furniture Corporation, and the Cavalier Corporation. Gaston married Marian Alexander Haskell in 1908. The couple had five children, Alice Van Yeveren (1909-1916), William Gaston (b. 1911), Marian Haskell (b. 1913), Rosine (b. 1915), and Dorothea Van Yeveren (b. 1917). Gaston died in 1960.
    Materials of Gaston C. Raoul include his letters to family members (1886-1949), a few letters from relatives and business associates (1882-1939), and a journal he kept while attending Lawrenceville School in New Jersey and working as a rodman in Kentucky (1888-1890). Also included in the subseries is a small group of letters from Gaston's wife Marian Haskell Raoul to Mary Wadley Raoul (1907-1912).
    The bulk of Gaston Raoul's letters date between 1888 and 1910 and are primarily to his mother. The earliest letters describe his activities at the Lawrenceville School (1888-1889), road-building work with the Kentucky Union Railroad (1890) and the Savannah Construction Company (1890-1891), and family life in Atlanta (1891-1894). From 1894 to 1897, Gaston worked for his father on the Mexican National Railroad, and letters from this period discuss his work on the lines and in the telegraph offices, his relationships with the Mexicans, and his despondency over his future. Subsequent attempts to find a career are documented by letters written while he worked as a division supervisor with the Central of Georgia Railroad in Macon and Alabama (1897-1899), as purchasing agent for the Mexican National Railroad in New York (1899-1,303), as a partner with the ship brokerage firm of J. F. Minis and Company in Savannah (1903-1904), and finally as president of the Keyser Manufacturing Company in Chattanooga (1905-1949). In addition to business ventures, Gaston discussed typhoid and yellow fever epidemics in the South (1898), and his extensive readings, travels, social activities, his family, and personal affairs.
    - Letters of Gaston C. Raoul, 1886-1957
    - 1886-1887 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 1888, January-April (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - 1888, May-June (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - 1888, September-December (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - 1889, January-June (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - 1889, September-December (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 1890, January-March (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - 1890, April-December (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - 1891, January-March (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - 1891, April-October (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - 1892-1893 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - 1894 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - 1895, January-April (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - 1895, May-August (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - 1895, September-December (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - 1896, January-May (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - 1896, June-September (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - 1896, October-December (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - 1897, January-March (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - 1897, April-August (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - 1897, September-December (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - 1898, January-February (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - 1898, March-April (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - 1898, May-September (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - 1898, October-December (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - 1899, January-March (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - 1899, April-November (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - 1900 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - 1901, January-February (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - 1901, March-May (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - 1901, June-December (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - 1902, January-April (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - 1902, May-July (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - 1902, August-December (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - 1903, January-April (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - 1903, May-August (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - 1903, September-December (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - 1904, January-April (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - 1904, May-July (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - 1904, August-December (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - 1905, January-June (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 1905, July-December (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 1906, January-April (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - 1906, May-December (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - 1907 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - 1908 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - 1909, January-July (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - 1909, August-October (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - 1910 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - 1911-1912 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - 1916-1957 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Letters from various persons, 1882-1940 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Other papers
    - Journal, 1888 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Journal, 1889-1890 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - "Being a Discursive Account of a Dilatory Journey from Great Hill to Chattanooga, Net Distance Covered, 210 Miles, Elapsed Time, 31 Years, 1874-1905 by Gaston Cesar Raoul, 29 September 1959 (copy) (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "Being a Discursive Account of a Dilatory Journey from Great Hill to Chattanooga, Net Distance Covered, 210 Miles, Elapsed Time, 31 Years, 1874-1905 by Gaston Cesar Raoul, 29 September 1959 (annotated copy) (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Clipping: Gaston C. Raoul on Georgia Tech football team (1893) (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Tribute by Cavalier Corporation, September 1960 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Letters of Marian Haskell Raoul
    - 1907-1908 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - 1909 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - 1910-1912 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Thomas Wadley Raoul papers, 1886-1933, Subseries 1.7; Personal name.; Box 23-23c
    Thomas Wadley Raoul was born in Macon, Georgia, on August 13, 1876. He was educated in Savannah and New York before entering college at the Georgia Institute of Technology. In 1896, while he was employed with the cotton firm S. M. Inman and Company in Macon, he became ill with tuberculosis. During the years between 1897 and 1909, he travelled widely in the Western United States and in Europe, seeking to cure his illness. His permanent home during this period and afterwards was Asheville, North Carolina, where he managed the Raoul family's resort establishment, Albemarle Park, until 1920. From 1921 until his death in 1953, he was president of the Biltmore Forest Company and served as treasurer and clerk of the town of Biltmore Forest. He was president and director of the Asheville Chamber of Commerce and a member of the North Carolina Park Commission. He married Helen Doyle Bennett in 1910, and had two daughters, Kathleen (b. 1913) and Jane (b. 1915).